<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | Casal Partiu]]></title>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-14T18:33:23-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://casalpartiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinícius Teles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ohrid]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/ohrid"/>
    <updated>2014-03-12T13:30:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/ohrid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-_5v4V2h4aW4/UyNVQMp_BNI/AAAAAAAAACQ/crxS4GQjS8M/s1600/ohridweb.jpg" width="800" height="329" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">
</div>


<p>This beautiful picture was taken by <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Ohrid">Ohrid</a>, where we arrived today. It's a beautiful town, by the lake, in an European country that has a very <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonia_naming_dispute">controversial name</a>. It calls itself <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Republic of Macedonia</a>. But, in international organizations, like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/United_Nations">UN</a>, the country is known as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonia_naming_dispute">FYROM</a> (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonia_naming_dispute">Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia</a>). The Greeks, their neighbors, don't agree with the use of the name <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a> for several reasons.</p>

<p>As a Brazilian, no matter how much I try to understand the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonia_naming_dispute">controversy around the name</a>, I believe I can't and shouldn't take sides. As in all kinds of complex controversies, each side has a long list of arguments to defend their views. As far as I'm concerned, I prefer to be completely out of this discussion.</p>

<p>But, when I talk about this country, I have to choose a name, so that I can communicate about it. I choose to write <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a>, just because it's simpler, not because I support one side or the other.</p>

<p>I have Greek friends that I like a lot and I know they don't approve this use, as much as I have friends in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a> that don't approve the other use. I want all of you to know that I'll use <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a> because whichever name I choose, people will be upset with me. Please just know that I still love you guys. I just want to simplify my writing. Remember, I'm not taking sides.</p>

<h2>The Balkans</h2>

<p>Having said that, let me tell you what has happened in the last weeks. While most people were parting in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Brazil">Brazil</a>, during <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazilian_Carnival">Carnival</a>, we were very far from the party, in a country that most Brazilians don't know much about, called <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a>.</p>

<p>We didn't have any expectations about it. But it turned out to be one of the most amazing surprises we've ever had in ours trips. The reason for that is simple: people.</p>

<p>The people of <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a> treated us like we've never been treated before outside of <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Brazil">Brazil</a>. To the point that I believe Serbians are the closest that you could possibly get from Brazilians in so many ways. The only noticeable difference is that they smoke way more than Brazilians, which is sad. Apart from that, we're incredibly similar. Both peoples are absolutely warm and friendly.</p>

<p>From the moment we stepped in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a> to the moment we left it, we've been busy meeting people. The days we spent in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Belgrade">Belgrade</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a>'s capital city, were so intense and joyful that we had a hard time to leave the city. So much so, that we extended our stay twice. And we would stay much longer, but our curiosity to visit the other countries in the <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Balkans">Balkans</a> forced us to move on.</p>

<p>Our stay in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a> will be remembered forever as one of the best parts of our trips, along with places like <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Turkey">Turkey</a> and a few others. Eventually we managed to come to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a> (greek friends, pretend you read <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonia_naming_dispute">FYROM</a> and don't be upset, please).</p>

<p>We took a bus from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Belgrade">Belgrade</a> to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Ni%C5%A1">Niš</a>, spent a night in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Ni%C5%A1">Niš</a>, then took another bus to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Skopje">Skopje</a>, the capital city of <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a>, where we planed to stay for two nights.</p>

<h2>The "hangover"</h2>

<p>Unfortunately, the intense days in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Belgrade">Belgrade</a> left some consequences. And <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> was the one who felt them.</p>

<p>She arrived in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Skopje">Skopje</a> feeling quite bad. Coughing, tired and with fever. The weather wasn't good, which only made things worse. Eventually we had to see a doctor.</p>

<p>Visiting a doctor is always undesirable when we're traveling, but once again we got lucky. We asked our <a href="https://airbnb.com/rooms/579046">Airbnb hosts</a> to recommend us a doctor, or a hospital. What they did instead was amazing and, at the same time, an example of how awesome people can be in this part of the world. They sent me a message saying: one of us is coming to pick you up in a few minutes and take you to the hospital. And that's exactly what happened.</p>

<p>Our host came by car and took us to an excellent private hospital. He talked in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Macedonian_language">Macedonian</a> with the receptionist and an English-speaking doctor saw <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> about half an hour later.</p>

<p>Given the symptoms, we thought she could be suffering of pneumonia, but fortunately, the doctor confirmed that this wasn't the case. She had bronchitis, probably caused and aggravated by several days with not enough sleep and exposure to a lot of smoke, since in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a>, people smoke a lot, even in closed places. This is the only complain we have about <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Serbia">Serbia</a>, by the way.</p>

<p><a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> got a prescription and we headed back to the receptionist. Time to make the payment and find out how much it costed to see the doctor. The price was 800 Macedonian Denars, which is equivalent to US$ 18.</p>

<p>I was in shock, since I expected it to be much higher. I mean, this is <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Europe">Europe</a>, after all. True, it's not <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Western_Europe">Western Europe</a>. Still, US$ 18 is quite cheap to see a doctor.</p>

<p>We have insurance and I could claim a reimbursement, but seriously, I won't even care to do that. The time and effort it will take me, just don't pay off.</p>

<p>We extended our stay in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Skopje">Skopje</a>, so that <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> could recover and she was enough better today, that we could finally come to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Ohrid">Ohrid</a>, which happens to be one the most beautiful places in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Republic_of_Macedonia">Macedonia</a>. Specially today, when we had this incredibly beautiful weather.</p>

<h2>Low cost around the Balkans</h2>

<p>By the way, speaking of low costs, my jaw dropped when I realized that I could rent an excellent apartment, with good reviews and all kinds of things that we generally need, in an excellent location, close to the lake, for only 17 Euros per/night (for the whole apartment).</p>

<p>Yes, I know it's low season, but still, 17 Euros for an apartment like this, is quite unbelievable. The host is great (even picked us up in the bus station) and the apartment turns out to be even better than expected.</p>

<p>Once again, we'll have to extend our stay.  This place is just perfect to work, enjoy, take great pictures and spend some time.</p>

<p>For what we could see so far, the <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Balkans">Balkans</a> turn out to be one of the most amazing and underrated destinations we've ever been to. Really glad that we're here and quite curious to visit the next destinations in the region.</p>

<p>By the way, we recorded lots of videos in the places that we've visited before, like <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Sofia">Sofia</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Veliko_Turnovo">Velinko Tarnovo</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Sinaia">Sinaia</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Brasov">Brasov</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Sibiu">Sibiu</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Timi%C5%9Foara">Timişoara</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Belgrade">Belgrade</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Novi_Sad">Novi Sad</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Ni%C5%A1">Niš</a> and <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Skopje">Skopje</a>. As you can imagine, it's a lot of work to edit and publish all of them. It's specially challenging because I have to balance this with my regular work. Still, I'm doing my best and hopefully you'll have a chance to see some cool videos very soon.</p>

<p>For now, please enjoy some of the incredbily beautiful pictures that <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> took around here.</p>

<div class="center">

<img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-ZWmaJT14PmU/UyNU3NVlZSI/AAAAAAAAABk/OLOCQFN8zK8/s1600/_DSC0900.jpg" width="800" height="532" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

<img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-MHiHmY9G5Us/UyNUxVBRgpI/AAAAAAAAABY/6JPWz9LAZ_0/s1600/_DSC0791.jpg" width="800" height="532" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

<img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-PT2tOKdjOAw/UyNVMTd5RPI/AAAAAAAAACI/zx6JiFr7KZs/s1600/_DSC1094.jpg" width="800" height="532" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

<img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-k-NFI1dNgm4/UyNVK49az7I/AAAAAAAAACA/fdR_OUxHekM/s1600/_DSC1051.jpg" width="800" height="532" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

<img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-V7IFawLYGIE/UyNU6MRdo3I/AAAAAAAAABw/qpr52ZnnfG0/s1600/_DSC1044.jpg" width="800" height="357" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

<img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-w5m6bhnXl3U/UyNVDsQofiI/AAAAAAAAAB4/NSuHFjcXOTw/s1600/_DSC1070.jpg" width="800" height="532" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">


<img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-hXrj47eWAg8/UyNU3_Cz0HI/AAAAAAAAABo/I8408Ba9YTg/s1600/_DSC0820.jpg" width="532" height="800" title="Ohrid, Macedonia">

</div>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Would you travel for 14 years? Earl did it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T13:30:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-_wHNZHsBMs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>We took the wrong car in the Metro. But that's how we met <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by chance. It happened here, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, a few days ago.</p>

<p>Who is <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by the way? He's the guy who taught me how to come from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a> by land. Or, most importantly, he's the person who's been traveling for over 14 years.</p>

<p>We were in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> a few days ago trying to figure out how to come to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Veliko_Turnovo">Velinko Ternovo</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>. I searched on Google and I found <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Earl's blog</a>, called <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Wandering Earl</a>. He made the trip the other way around. Still, the information he shared was very useful to us.</p>

<p>That would be more than enough to make my day. But <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">his blog</a> turns out to be very good and useful. I couldn't stop reading it and I learned a ton about other countries in the <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Balkans">Balkans</a>, which we'll be visiting soon.</p>

<p>I knew he was in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, but I thought he'd probably be too busy. I didn't plan to contact him or anything like that.</p>

<p>Imagine my astonishment when I saw him in front of me in the Metro car! It was him, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>. It was the most bizarre experience I've had in a long time. What are the odds of this happening? And I even took the subway in the wrong direction by mistake, which rarely happens to me.</p>

<p>I spent so much time reading his articles in the last few days and all of the sudden he was standing in front of me, in the subway of a big city. You don't bump into a celebrity in the Metro everyday, right? Nor do I. And, being an introvert, I thought to myself: what do I do? Should I talk to him?</p>

<p>I told <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com">Pati</a> about it and she said: you must talk to him now. If you don't, I'll do it. A small discussion between us followed. Somehow I found the courage to say: hi, are you <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>?</p>

<p>Fortunately, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a> is a nice guy, as I was about to find out. He was also amazed by the coincidence when I told him what was happening.</p>

<p>I contacted him later, we had dinner together and it was such a pleasure to talk to him. Then I figured out that my friends should also have a chance to hear what he has to say about permanent traveling.</p>

<p>I invited him for this interview and he was once again very generous with his time. He has a wonderful perspective on several topics. And I think it's pretty hard to dismiss your desire to travel after watching what he has to say in this video.</p>

<p>Would you have his courage and travel permanently for most of your adult life?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel to learn about future episodes.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visit to Plovdiv in Bulgaria]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/visit-to-plovdiv-in-bulgaria"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/visit-to-plovdiv-in-bulgaria</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XgYAhTTG684" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Get to know <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>'s second largest city. Join us in a tour around the streets of this picturesque Bulgarian city.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trip from Turkey to Bulgaria by bus]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/trip-from-turkey-to-bulgaria-by-bus"/>
    <updated>2014-02-07T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/trip-from-turkey-to-bulgaria-by-bus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XuwjggqbVNE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>We traveled from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Istanbul">Istanbul</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Turkey">Turkey</a>, to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>. See what happens in the border and learn some curiosities about <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>.</p>

<p>These are the music used in this video in order of appearance:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ork_Zlatni_Makedoncinja/Live_at_the_2013_Golden_Festival_1545/Milionerce_Dada_Sali">Milionerce Dada Sali</a> by <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ork_Zlatni_Makedoncinja/">Zlatni Makedoncinja</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ornamatik/Live_at_the_2014_Golden_Festival_1808/Bufcan_Sko">Bufcan Sko</a> by <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ornamatik/">Ornamatik</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>They are released as <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a>.</p>

<p>The apartment you see in the video was rented on <a href="http://www.airbnb.com/c/vteles">Airbnb</a>. If you plan to visit <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, this is <a href="https://airbnb.com/rooms/270888">the apartment you see in the video</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visas]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/visas"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/visas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6ZK76-J9mbM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Many people ask us how we deal with visas as we travel the world. Here is the answer.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
