<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | Casal Partiu]]></title>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-19T20:41:57-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://casalpartiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinícius Teles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Would you travel for 14 years? Earl did it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T13:30:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-_wHNZHsBMs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>We took the wrong car in the Metro. But that's how we met <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by chance. It happened here, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, a few days ago.</p>

<p>Who is <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by the way? He's the guy who taught me how to come from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a> by land. Or, most importantly, he's the person who's been traveling for over 14 years.</p>

<p>We were in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> a few days ago trying to figure out how to come to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Veliko_Turnovo">Velinko Ternovo</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>. I searched on Google and I found <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Earl's blog</a>, called <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Wandering Earl</a>. He made the trip the other way around. Still, the information he shared was very useful to us.</p>

<p>That would be more than enough to make my day. But <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">his blog</a> turns out to be very good and useful. I couldn't stop reading it and I learned a ton about other countries in the <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Balkans">Balkans</a>, which we'll be visiting soon.</p>

<p>I knew he was in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, but I thought he'd probably be too busy. I didn't plan to contact him or anything like that.</p>

<p>Imagine my astonishment when I saw him in front of me in the Metro car! It was him, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>. It was the most bizarre experience I've had in a long time. What are the odds of this happening? And I even took the subway in the wrong direction by mistake, which rarely happens to me.</p>

<p>I spent so much time reading his articles in the last few days and all of the sudden he was standing in front of me, in the subway of a big city. You don't bump into a celebrity in the Metro everyday, right? Nor do I. And, being an introvert, I thought to myself: what do I do? Should I talk to him?</p>

<p>I told <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com">Pati</a> about it and she said: you must talk to him now. If you don't, I'll do it. A small discussion between us followed. Somehow I found the courage to say: hi, are you <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>?</p>

<p>Fortunately, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a> is a nice guy, as I was about to find out. He was also amazed by the coincidence when I told him what was happening.</p>

<p>I contacted him later, we had dinner together and it was such a pleasure to talk to him. Then I figured out that my friends should also have a chance to hear what he has to say about permanent traveling.</p>

<p>I invited him for this interview and he was once again very generous with his time. He has a wonderful perspective on several topics. And I think it's pretty hard to dismiss your desire to travel after watching what he has to say in this video.</p>

<p>Would you have his courage and travel permanently for most of your adult life?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel to learn about future episodes.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visit to Plovdiv in Bulgaria]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/visit-to-plovdiv-in-bulgaria"/>
    <updated>2014-02-14T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/visit-to-plovdiv-in-bulgaria</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XgYAhTTG684" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Get to know <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>'s second largest city. Join us in a tour around the streets of this picturesque Bulgarian city.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trip from Turkey to Bulgaria by bus]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/trip-from-turkey-to-bulgaria-by-bus"/>
    <updated>2014-02-07T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/trip-from-turkey-to-bulgaria-by-bus</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/XuwjggqbVNE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>We traveled from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Istanbul">Istanbul</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Turkey">Turkey</a>, to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>. See what happens in the border and learn some curiosities about <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>.</p>

<p>These are the music used in this video in order of appearance:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ork_Zlatni_Makedoncinja/Live_at_the_2013_Golden_Festival_1545/Milionerce_Dada_Sali">Milionerce Dada Sali</a> by <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ork_Zlatni_Makedoncinja/">Zlatni Makedoncinja</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ornamatik/Live_at_the_2014_Golden_Festival_1808/Bufcan_Sko">Bufcan Sko</a> by <a href="http://freemusicarchive.org/music/Ornamatik/">Ornamatik</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>They are released as <a href="http://creativecommons.org">Creative Commons</a>.</p>

<p>The apartment you see in the video was rented on <a href="http://www.airbnb.com/c/vteles">Airbnb</a>. If you plan to visit <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Plovdiv">Plovdiv</a>, this is <a href="https://airbnb.com/rooms/270888">the apartment you see in the video</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Visas]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/visas"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/visas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/6ZK76-J9mbM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Many people ask us how we deal with visas as we travel the world. Here is the answer.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Would you like a tour in Istanbul?]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-like-a-tour-in-istanbul"/>
    <updated>2014-01-24T14:30:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-like-a-tour-in-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/Mmz1jtE2gBc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>"Wow, I'd never come to this place if you haven't brought me here. What a fantastic place!" That's what we said many times in the past, when a friend guided us around a city he or she was living in.</p>

<p>The experience of visiting a new place is so much better when we have a chance to see it through the eyes of a person who lives there. Besides the touristic spots, we have the opportunity to visit hidden parts of the city that locals go to quite often, but the tourists don't even imagine that exist. And you know what? Those are typically the best parts.</p>

<p>Here, in Istanbul, we've met <a href="http://www.turistambul.com/pt/#!/page_Services">Michele</a>, a Brazilian lady who's been living here for almost a decade. After showing the city to so many friends in the past, she realized she could go beyond that. She created a concierge service and began to show Istanbul to people from all over the world, exactly in the same way she was doing before with her friends.</p>

<p>The concierge service eventually became an agency called <a href="http://www.turistambul.com">Turistambul</a>. The best part of it is the personalized experience that <a href="http://www.turistambul.com/pt/#!/page_Services">Michele</a> delivers, which mix the classic tourism with local and authentic aspects of the city, known only by those living here. This mix and her kindness have been attracting many tourists from all over the world.</p>

<p>We've spent several days with <a href="http://www.turistambul.com/pt/#!/page_Services">Michele</a> recently, since <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> was shooting pictures for a promotional campaign featuring <a href="http://www.turistambul.com">Turistambul</a>. At the end, <a href="http://www.turistambul.com/pt/#!/page_Services">Michele</a> managed to set aside some time and we interviewed her.</p>

<p><a href="http://patriciafigueira.com.br">Pati</a> and <a href="http://www.viniciusteles.com.br">I</a> don't do a lot of tourism ourselves. But Istanbul is such an amazing city. Many people would love to come here for a few days and do some tourism. That's why we thought it was worth to ask <a href="http://www.turistambul.com/pt/#!/page_Services">Michele</a> a bit more about what one can expect when visiting Istanbul.</p>

<p>Learn more about <a href="http://www.turistambul.com">Turistambul</a> at: <a href="http://www.turistambul.com">http://www.turistambul.com/</a>.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel learn about future episodes easily.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
