<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: earl | Casal Partiu]]></title>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/blog/categories/earl/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-16T10:34:44-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://casalpartiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinícius Teles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Would you travel for 14 years? Earl did it.]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T13:30:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/would-you-travel-for-14-years-earl-did-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="center">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/-_wHNZHsBMs" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>We took the wrong car in the Metro. But that's how we met <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by chance. It happened here, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, a few days ago.</p>

<p>Who is <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>, by the way? He's the guy who taught me how to come from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a> by land. Or, most importantly, he's the person who's been traveling for over 14 years.</p>

<p>We were in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a> a few days ago trying to figure out how to come to <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bucharest">Bucharest</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, from <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Veliko_Turnovo">Velinko Ternovo</a>, in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Bulgaria">Bulgaria</a>. I searched on Google and I found <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Earl's blog</a>, called <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">Wandering Earl</a>. He made the trip the other way around. Still, the information he shared was very useful to us.</p>

<p>That would be more than enough to make my day. But <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/">his blog</a> turns out to be very good and useful. I couldn't stop reading it and I learned a ton about other countries in the <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Balkans">Balkans</a>, which we'll be visiting soon.</p>

<p>I knew he was in <a href="http://wikitravel.org/en/Romania">Romania</a>, but I thought he'd probably be too busy. I didn't plan to contact him or anything like that.</p>

<p>Imagine my astonishment when I saw him in front of me in the Metro car! It was him, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>. It was the most bizarre experience I've had in a long time. What are the odds of this happening? And I even took the subway in the wrong direction by mistake, which rarely happens to me.</p>

<p>I spent so much time reading his articles in the last few days and all of the sudden he was standing in front of me, in the subway of a big city. You don't bump into a celebrity in the Metro everyday, right? Nor do I. And, being an introvert, I thought to myself: what do I do? Should I talk to him?</p>

<p>I told <a href="http://patriciafigueira.com">Pati</a> about it and she said: you must talk to him now. If you don't, I'll do it. A small discussion between us followed. Somehow I found the courage to say: hi, are you <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a>?</p>

<p>Fortunately, <a href="http://www.wanderingearl.com/about/">Earl</a> is a nice guy, as I was about to find out. He was also amazed by the coincidence when I told him what was happening.</p>

<p>I contacted him later, we had dinner together and it was such a pleasure to talk to him. Then I figured out that my friends should also have a chance to hear what he has to say about permanent traveling.</p>

<p>I invited him for this interview and he was once again very generous with his time. He has a wonderful perspective on several topics. And I think it's pretty hard to dismiss your desire to travel after watching what he has to say in this video.</p>

<p>Would you have his courage and travel permanently for most of your adult life?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/subscription_center?add_user=CasalPartiuEng">Subscribe to the YouTube channel to learn about future episodes.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
