<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: couch surfing | Casal Partiu]]></title>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/blog/categories/couch-surfing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-17T16:00:00-02:00</updated>
  <id>http://casalpartiu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Vinícius Teles]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Travel with a local guide]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/travel-with-local-guide"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T15:46:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/travel-with-local-guide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="165" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-oCShpa8SMX4/UPghtgkKpzI/AAAAAAAAAQ0/I_F58Zdeqj8/s640/istambul_pan2.jpg" width="640" alt="Panorama of the Golden Horn"></center>
</p>


<p>
  We've been in Istanbul for two weeks mostly working at home. But we've managed to have great moments with some amazing people in the few times we left. And since there's an important lesson we've learnt, I'll describe some events to illustrate it.
</p>


<p>
  <b>Turkish breakfast</b>
</p>


<p>
  We've met some nice people on the three Couch Surfing meetups that we attended in Istanbul. Among them, there was this great couple, Anna and Cenk. She's German, he's Turkish.
</p>


<p>
  We chatted a lot in the last meeting and they invited us to a traditional Turkish breakfast on Saturday, followed by a walking tour. The restaurant is called Hatay Sofrası and it serves Hatay specialties. If I understood it correctly, Hatay cuisine is very appreciated and Cenk told me this restaurant serves some of the best Hatay food in town.
</p>


<p>
  We were a party of five people. Lisa, a friendly young lady from Austria, is spending a couple of months in Istanbul. She also met Anna and Cenk at a Couch Surfing meetup and they invited her to join us.
</p>


<p>
  We binged like there's no tomorrow and we loved the food, the explanations, the company and the whole experience. And that was just the beginning.
</p>


<p>
  <b>Walking tour</b>
</p>


<p>
  After breakfast Cenk took us around the streets of Fatih. We stopped in front of a bakery and Cenk described each of the breads inside. Then we walked to the Fatih Mosque and finally we made it to the honey shop that Cenk has told us about during breakfast.
</p>


<p>
  The owner is very hospitable and knowledgeable. He explained the properties of several of the honeys on stock. Always making sure that we were tasting a little bit of each. I don't remember another moment in my life that I tried as much honey.
</p>


<p>
  There is a special kind of honey called "crazy honey". It's special because you can only eat a little bit of it. Otherwise you're in trouble. It's made of the nectar of a highly toxic plant indigenous to the Black Sea. So if you eat more than a small spoon of it per day, you begin to feel symptoms like illness, nausea and hallucinations.
</p>


<p>
  Overconsumption of this honey is dangerous, but small quantities are good for health. Do you think we got scared after listening the stories? Sure we did. Even armies where defeated with the help of this honey. But our adventurous spirits couldn't resist the temptation of tasting and buying a small jar. So far, we've been eating a little bit of it every day and we're still alive and kicking. Yeah!
</p>


<p>
  <b>Tasting tour</b>
</p>


<p>
  We resumed our journey and soon enough we were in the middle of a square, near the Valens Aqueduct. Cenk pointed to a restaurant that serves one of the best Kebabs in town. At this point, we had already forgotten we've eaten a huge breakfast. So we decided to try a durum (wrap). Delicious, of course.
</p>


<p>
  We moved on but not for long. We saw a place selling rice mixed with chicken and chickpeas. Cenk told us that stalls selling this mix usually proliferate on the streets of Taksim late at night to cater for the people coming back from the night clubs. Since it's so typical of Istanbul, we had to taste it, right?
</p>


<p>
  Boza time! We went to this old establishment to try&nbsp;Boza&nbsp; It's a fermented drink that tastes like, well,&nbsp;Boza.&nbsp; I liked it, but Patricia wasn't as enthusiastic. We mix it with toasted chickpeas that Cenk bought across the street. I haven't eaten these before. But I really liked it.
</p>


<p>
  Back to the walk we wandered through old narrow streets until we arrive at the Süleymaniye Mosque, the largest mosque of Istanbul. Very beautiful interior and magnificent views from the gardens. Great explanations from Cenk.
</p>


<p>
  Almost across the street there was this cafe with a privileged view of the Golden Horn. Time to take some pictures and drink some tea. It was raining most of the time during this walk. But who cares? With so many interesting things to see and delicious food to taste, we'd not be put off by rain.
</p>


<p>
  From there we descended to the Spice Bazaar. And, of course, it was necessary to do a brief stop at this small restaurant that serves delicious&nbsp;kofta. Then a stop at another place to buy some spices. And the other one to buy some Turkish coffee, until we finally arrive at one of the most important places of the day. The one that sells the best Baklava, of course. :-)
</p>


<p>
  Busy day you'd say. But it wasn't over yet. We took the ferry and went to the Asian side where we called the day at the bar of this authentic restaurant with a good pint of Efes. I probably should mention that brain was offered among the appetizers, but no, we didn't try it. We still need to teach our brains to accept it as a kind of food. :-)
</p>


<p>
  <b>Lesson learned</b>
</p>


<p>
  Could we have done all of this on our own?&nbsp;Theoretically, yes. But pay attention, because the devil is in the details.
</p>


<p>
  Even if we had done a careful research about all of these places beforehand, and even if we had gone to all of these places on our own, it wouldn't be anything close to what we experienced and&nbsp;definitely&nbsp;not as rewarding. Why? Because visiting a place with a local is a completely different history.
</p>


<p>
  To mention only one example, when we visited the&nbsp;Süleymaniye Mosque, Cenk pointed me several details about the interior and about the life that went on around the mosque long time ago. He explained the role of the hamam near the mosque, the&nbsp;beauty of the Friday prayers, some details about Islam and his personal views about the way people sometimes twist the teachings of the Koran to take some kind of advantage.
</p>


<p>
  These explanations and points of view help us make a picture of the city, the country and it's culture that is much richer than what we could have learnt without a local. And in this case, it was even richer because Anna has been living here for a while, but she's not Turkish. She's a foreigner like ourselves, with a deeper understanding of the local culture, but aware of the things that would naturally call the attention of newcomers. So her inputs complemented Cenk's and helped us to picture this place in a way that we couldn't imagine before.
</p>


<p>
  We can't thank Cenk, Anna and Lisa enough for their company and for all that we've learned with them. Hope we'll be able to&nbsp;reattribute&nbsp;somehow. And I also hope that we've learnt this lesson carefully and try very hard to meet local people everywhere we go from now on.
</p>


<p>
  In fact, I believe most travelers should try to apply this lesson on their trips, cause it's an amazing way to make the trip much more colorful and entertaining. Besides, it's fun and we get to make good friends.
</p>


<p>
  And remember, as I wrote before, Couch Surfing is a great way to meet local people and fellow travelers.
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="332" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AhIlZa0ImTU/UPghIJIUFvI/AAAAAAAAAPA/R4F_nHx7eAI/s640/Pan1_istambul.jpg" width="640" alt="Dolmabahçe Mosque and the&nbsp;Bosphorus Bridge"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-FE8l7zm890U/UPghNSc4lnI/AAAAAAAAAPQ/A1maqFXlBzY/s640/istambul_0004.jpg" width="640" alt="Dolmabahçe Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-qFS26vT2zZs/UPghOxwnjuI/AAAAAAAAAPY/r_9gbMQphUc/s640/istambul_0003.jpg" width="424" alt="Beautiful lamps on the streets of Taksim"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-gHmUtrf2f6g/UPghIziFyqI/AAAAAAAAAPE/xOXO4C1KikE/s640/istambul_0001.jpg" width="424" alt="Wandering the streets of Taksim"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-VZE2_CD95vk/UPghUHJ6waI/AAAAAAAAAPk/Oew9prJvOGQ/s640/istambul_0002.jpg" width="640" alt="Restaurantes and cafés everywhere in Taksim"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-IxpQX-W6TzM/UPghTyJTZXI/AAAAAAAAAPg/FNy0sKqwnPU/s640/istambul_0023.jpg" width="640" alt="Anna tasting honey"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/--40WBTvE-3o/UPghVEJVOdI/AAAAAAAAAPs/jUKFD_J9poA/s640/istambul_0024.jpg" width="426" alt="Arriving at Süleymaniye Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-C5EchJs62OE/UPghnAoBVwI/AAAAAAAAAQY/QdYqRkweRBw/s640/istambul_0048.jpg" width="424" alt="Patricia's self picture in the gardens of Süleymaniye Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-dR9J9DAQpiU/UPghbrp-ksI/AAAAAAAAAP4/cWvpG7bzQrw/s640/istambul_0050.jpg" width="424" alt="Reflection of Süleymaniye Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-ylZl5HPnYqc/UPghcDbmisI/AAAAAAAAAP8/Gd4isfExkUs/s640/istambul_0030.jpg" width="640" alt="Anna, Lisa, Cenk and Vinicius at Süleymaniye Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-gzcuE1W-m_8/UPghiF-PMyI/AAAAAAAAAQI/2bZTIcR1ci8/s640/istambul_0093.jpg" width="640" alt="Cenk, Anna and Vinicius at Haydarpaşa Gari on the Asian side"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-y-9JVn7uOSs/UPghiK1YXsI/AAAAAAAAAQM/_kk07cUXPW8/s640/istambul_0094.jpg" width="424" alt="Beautiful building of the Haydarpaşa Gari on the Asian side"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="306" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-e9_zgPvOhVo/UPgh0NfcEFI/AAAAAAAAARc/V49m1aKbGSY/s640/istambul_pan3.jpg" width="640" alt="Roman cistern"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ynECENdi7tE/UPghtDV9IKI/AAAAAAAAAQw/_cmfgWCia6o/s640/istambul_0130.jpg" width="640" alt="Vinícius learning about the Roman Cistern"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-PzAt6zZY_X8/UPghoZKR_RI/AAAAAAAAAQg/62kS_L4nVgQ/s640/istambul_0129.jpg" width="424" alt="Fish in the Roman Cistern"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-Pk9mOL3dA2s/UPghunGOZaI/AAAAAAAAARA/Yv8YiR82jwc/s640/istambul_0182.jpg" width="640" alt="Bagel street seller and Hagia Sofia on the background"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="318" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-kzPu8gkyGJ4/UPghy6LN6sI/AAAAAAAAARQ/eDb-XYUmltw/s640/istambul_pan5.jpg" width="640" alt="Blue Mosque at dusk"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="640" src="http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-axxysgdiDEU/UPgh5C8HqgI/AAAAAAAAARo/MVnDvzoIYF0/s640/p_istambul_0101.jpg" width="424" alt="Interior of the Blue Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="424" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-GPEwrTGYYHg/UPghoTnD5NI/AAAAAAAAAQk/5UBb_eB2EXc/s640/istambul_0114.jpg" width="640" alt="Interior of the Blue Mosque"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="429" src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-AJ7BXwQH-Po/UPghxImYkJI/AAAAAAAAARI/2QKA92Doco4/s640/istambul_pan4.jpg" width="640" alt="Blue Mosque under the sunset"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="130" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-QPLzG83SCNU/UPgh0IowxEI/AAAAAAAAARY/C8mAKUfeV5s/s640/istambul_pan7_cs6.jpg" width="640" alt="Black and white panorama of the Golden Horn"></center>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Couch Surfing]]></title>
    <link href="http://casalpartiu.com/couch-surfing"/>
    <updated>2013-01-09T07:46:00-02:00</updated>
    <id>http://casalpartiu.com/couch-surfing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  You know that moment when you realize how stupid you've been? That's the feeling I've had for the last two days. Let me explain.
</p>


<p>
  We've been traveling around the world for more than two years now and I've always complained that I wanted an easy way to meet people wherever we go. Because meeting locals or other fellow travelers is always the best part of the journey. But how can someone arrive in a new city and connect with people?
</p>


<p>
  It's actually pretty easy and the solution has always been on the tip of my fingers. I just haven't tried it before, until yesterday. And I guess many of you probably know that I'm talking about <a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>.
</p>


<p>
  <a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>&nbsp;is a web site created more than a decade ago. Say you've got a couch on your living room and you'd like to host a traveler. You go to http://www.couchsurfing.org, create a profile, tell the world that you have this awesome couch and soon enough people begin to ask you for a chance to stay at your place for a few days.
</p>


<p>
  You offer your couch, spare bed, room, or whatever as a courtesy. You can't charge for it on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>.&nbsp; On the other hand, if you travel using&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>&nbsp; you eventually stay in other person's place paying nothing for it. But you are generally more than welcome to show your appreciation with a gift, or teaching something from your country, like cooking a regional meal, for instance.
</p>


<p>
  That's super cool, right? But there's more. Couch Surfers organize lots of activities all year round. And everybody is welcome. Even people that never used Couch Surfing to travel, or to host, can participate. For instance, there are weekly meet ups in many cities. And that's how we finally joined&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>.
</p>


<p>
  In Istanbul, there are lots of weekly meet ups. There was one last night hosted in a bar basicly to socialize. There was another one tonight for English conversation. We've been to both and it was an amazing experience. How could we miss it for such a long time?
</p>


<p>
  Truth is that I knew about&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>&nbsp;for a while. But everytime I tried to use it, I got frustrated and kind of intimidated by the user interface. It's pretty confusing. I could never really overcome this barrier until this week. I told myself: you've got to try harder cause there's something great out there and you're missing it. And that turns out to be absolutely true.
</p>


<p>
  There were 30+ people last night and 40+ people tonight. Most of then are Turkish. So, those were just perfect places to meet local people as well as people from different origins that are living in Istanbul. But why were there so many people?
</p>


<p>
  I learnt yesterday that traveling abroad is not easy for the Turkish. Aparently, they have to apply for a visa for most of the countries they'd like to visit (fortunately they don't need a visa for Brazil). Anyway, many people just can't afford the trip. And learning English at school doesn't really work. English teaching is generally very poor in Turkey. Same thing in Brazil.
</p>


<p>
  But here some people really want to learn English. And since most of them probably can't afford to pay for a private English course, they like to attend meet ups to practice English with the foreigners that are visiting Istanbul. Which is absolutely wonderful for everybody.
</p>


<p>
  So they have those meetings every week and they are always packed with people. Pay attention to this important detail. Tonight is Saturday night! They meet to practice English on a Saturday night! That's really nice.
</p>


<p>
  Patricia and I talked to many people tonight. Most of them were Turkish indeed. But we also met people from Algeria, Canada, Armenia, Romania, Germany, Brazil, Bolivia and Luxemburg. And we learnt a bit about each of these places. As a matter of fact, I even learnt to play backgammon! And I won. Talk about beginers luck. :-)
</p>


<p>
  I deeply regret all the time I wasted not trying to use&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>.&nbsp; But I'm delighted that we've finally began to use it. And Istanbul seems to be just the perfect place, since people really use it a lot and it works incredbly well.
</p>


<p>
  You can check out my profile on&nbsp;<a href="https://www.couchsurfing.org/">Couch Surfing</a>&nbsp;at &nbsp;<a href="http://www.couchsurfing.org/people/vinicius.m.teles">http://www.couchsurfing.org/people/vinicius.m.teles</a>.
</p>


<p>
  <center><img height="424" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/--khjGz3XC4w/UO028BAQfgI/AAAAAAAAAN0/69zMziRoeBY/s640/cs-meetup.jpg" width="640"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="436" src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-y5PYs7lM7qA/UO027ssp19I/AAAAAAAAANs/82GX_aE3dn8/s640/cs-vinicius-and-omer.jpg" width="640"></center>
</p>


<p>
  <center><img border="0" height="416" src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-fQH6KsQeC9w/UO027j4Y1qI/AAAAAAAAANw/Jnghr0r4pwQ/s640/cs-vinicius-and-yacine.jpg" width="640"></center>
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
